# TROY GARDNER

Vancouver, Washington 98662 | (360) 901-7886 | troy.gardner71@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/troy-a-gardner

#### **SUMMARY**

A dedicated and detail-oriented **IT Business Consultant** with experience in enterprise asset management, database management, data integrity, project management, issue resolution, diagnostic testing, continuous improvement, solutions development and design, and evaluating and analyzing company data to identify opportunities for sustainable growth. Excels in building and developing strong client relationships within deadline-driven environments. Vast experience in internal and external communication, organization, leadership, teamwork, and collaboration. Established experience in resolving issues, driving successful data cleansing activities, and consistently exceeding client and company expectations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# TRIDENT SEAFOODS

## **Senior EAM Data Integrity Lead**

Tacoma, Washington 2021-2024

- Oversaw development, maintenance, and management of INFOR Enterprise Asset Management (EAM) system across nine corporate sites throughout Alaska and the continental U.S.
- Drove \$150K data cleansing project utilizing third-party resources, resulting in a standardized architecture, stabilized system, and 75% improvement in user efficiencies.
- Partnered with executive management on KPI monitoring and evaluation, mining data and generating custom dataspies and reporting for sites' overall inventory and maintenance efficiencies.
- Facilitated procure-to-pay process in collaboration with internal cross-functional teams for projected \$80M costs-saving measure across all business units.
- Orchestrated Lean strategies ensuring storeroom efficiencies across corporate plants for streamlined inventory management.
- Developed central depository for system documentation and training materials, utilizing SharePoint for use enterprise wide.
- Supported the integration of additional systems, such as SAP S / 4 HANA, for the P2P functionality.
- Worked closely with the SAP Master Data team to ensure that indirect parts and inventory data was accurate and followed current data formatting strategies.

#### TRIDENT SEAFOODS

## Tacoma, Washington 2020-2021

## **Continuous Improvement Lead (EAM - Global Supply Chain)**

- Supported company as key member of foundational core team, implementing Infor EAM by defining, designing, and delivering customized solutions across Alaska, Domestic, Vessel, and Support operations.
- Collaborated with site management and staff on EAM startup initiatives, overseeing key processes and infrastructure build out for 40% reduction in equipment downtime.
- Facilitated business transformation through documented EAM standard operating procedures for continued staff training and knowledge transfer.

CBRE

Troutdale, Oregon 2018-2020

### **CMMS Maintenance Planner, Scheduler (Amazon Fulfillment)**

- Analyzed maintenance work orders by size, urgency, skill set, location, complexity, and available manpower and assigned them to individual technicians or work teams accordingly.
- Projected planned maintenance work orders for automatic generation at predetermined and strategic intervals to minimize equipment downtime.
- Traveled to various Amazon locations throughout the country to participate in and lead CMMS trainings.
- Managed the collaboration and guidance of relevant subcontractors.
- Utilized guidelines set by Amazon management to develop, implement, and manage preventive maintenance and life cycle optimization strategies.

21TECH Kansas City, Missouri

### **Certified Infor EAM Consultant**

- Provided INFOR EAM technical consulting for Kansas City Area Transportation Authority.
- Served in technical analyst role on key enterprise asset management business process improvement and system implementation project.
- Established business requirements with end users.
- Developed technical designs and acted as liaison to development team.
- Educated clients on maintenance strategies and good maintenance practices.
- Defined business process flows, key performance indicators, and reporting requirements to support client's maintenance strategies.

#### **VOLT ENGINEERING SOLUTIONS**

Colorado Springs, Colorado

2016-2017

## **Quality Analyst (Contract Position - Intel Corporation, Aloha, Oregon)**

- Managed and prioritized work through R / D area while ensuring that consumables were stocked.
- Worked alongside engineers to develop process improvements and optimization.
- Maintained lines of communication across organization and neighboring business units.
- Provided department status updates to management and business unit leads.

#### ARCTIC SLOPE NATIVE ASSOCIATION

Barrow, Alaska 2015-2016

## **Maximo Database Analyst**

- Managed and maintained data storage and access, providing database support services to ensure continuous system availability.
- Identified areas of improvement, creating solutions to enhance department's health and wellness strategies while complying with HIPAA regulations.
- Updated database records and fixed software issues.
- Maintained standard data recovery processes to improve recoverability time.
- Reviewed contracts for vendors, contractors, and suppliers for complete and accurate information, escalating as needed.

**AOUITAS SOLUTIONS** Roswell, Georgia 2014-2015

## Certified Maximo EAM Consultant (ASNA - Samuel Simmonds Memorial Hospital)

- Managed assets of enterprise across departments, facilities, and business units.
- Integrated techniques for optimization throughout asset life cycle, including design, commissioning, operations, and replacement.
- Oversaw physical asset and infrastructure management, IT service management, digital asset management, fixed asset management, and emerging asset management, complying with organization's HIPAA regulations.

## **EDUCATION**

## UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX, Phoenix, Arizona B.S., Information Technology and Software Engineering

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

IBM Certified Deployment Professional, Maximo Asset Management Version 7.5 IBM Certified Deployment Professional, Tivoli Process Automation Engine Version 7.5 SQL Essential Training, LinkedIn Learning Center Infor EAM v11.3 Certification

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**